<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>REST on Unladen swallow - Olivier Wulveryck</title><link>https://owulveryck.github.io/tags/rest.html</link><description>Recent content in REST on Unladen swallow - Olivier Wulveryck</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Olivier Wulveryck</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 10:05:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owulveryck.github.io/tags/rest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Playing with (Openstack) Keystone</title><link>https://owulveryck.github.io/2015/11/17/playing-with-openstack-keystone.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 10:05:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://owulveryck.github.io/2015/11/17/playing-with-openstack-keystone.html</guid><description>In the cloud computing, alongside of the hosting monsters such as amazon or google, there is the Openstack Platform.
Openstack is not a single software, it is more a galaxy of components aim to control the infrastructure, such as hardware pools, storage, network. The management can then be done via a Web based interface or via a bunch of RESTful API.
I would like to evaluate its identity service named keystone and use it as a AuthN and AuthZ backend for my simple_iaas example.</description></item><item><title>Simple IaaS API documentation with swagger</title><link>https://owulveryck.github.io/2015/11/11/simple-iaas-api-documentation-with-swagger.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 14:24:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://owulveryck.github.io/2015/11/11/simple-iaas-api-documentation-with-swagger.html</guid><description>In a previous post I have explained how to develop a very simple API server.
Without the associated documentation, the API will be useless. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how we can use swagger-ui in this project to generate a beautiful documentation.
Note I&amp;rsquo;m blogging and experimenting, of course, in the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; life, it&amp;rsquo;s a lot better to code the API interface before implementing the middleware.
About Swagger Swagger is a framework. On top of the swagger project is composed of several tools.</description></item><item><title>IaaS-like RESTfull API based on microservices</title><link>https://owulveryck.github.io/2015/11/10/iaas-like-restfull-api-based-on-microservices.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 08:56:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://owulveryck.github.io/2015/11/10/iaas-like-restfull-api-based-on-microservices.html</guid><description>Abstracts Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at the principles of a middleware layer and especially on how a RESTFULL API could glue different IT services together.
I am reading more and more about the &amp;ldquo;API economy&amp;rdquo;
I&amp;rsquo;ve also seen this excellent video made by Mat Ryer about how to code an API in GO and why go would be the perfect language to code such a portal.
The problem I&amp;rsquo;m facing is that in the organization I&amp;rsquo;m working for, the developments are heterogeneous and therefore you can find ruby teams as well as python teams and myself as a go team (That will change in the future anyway) The key point is that I would like my middleware to serve as an entry point to the services provided by the department.</description></item></channel></rss>