<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>category on Unladen swallow - Olivier Wulveryck</title><link>https://owulveryck.github.io/categories/category/</link><description>Recent content in category on Unladen swallow - Olivier Wulveryck</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Olivier Wulveryck</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 21:03:52 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://owulveryck.github.io/categories/category/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From GraphQL to a table view with React and Apollo</title><link>https://owulveryck.github.io/2017/03/28/from-graphql-to-a-table-view-with-react-and-apollo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 21:03:52 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://owulveryck.github.io/2017/03/28/from-graphql-to-a-table-view-with-react-and-apollo/</guid><description>In the last post I have played with GraphQL. The next step is to actually query the data and display it.
In this post I will use react (from Facebook) and the Apollo GraphQL client.
Tooling React I won&amp;rsquo;t give in here an introduction of the language because you may find on the web thousands of very good tutorials and advocacy articles. Anyway I will explain briefly why I have chosen React.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Facebook&#39;s GraphQL (applied to AWS products and offers management)</title><link>https://owulveryck.github.io/2017/03/22/playing-with-facebooks-graphql-applied-to-aws-products-and-offers-management/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 09:15:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://owulveryck.github.io/2017/03/22/playing-with-facebooks-graphql-applied-to-aws-products-and-offers-management/</guid><description>About GraphQL GraphQL has been invented by Facebook for the purpose of refactoring their mobile application. Facebook had reached the limits of the standard REST API mainly because:
Getting that much information was requiring a huge amount of API endpoints The versioning of the API was counter-productive regarding Facebook&amp;rsquo;s frequents deployements. But graphql is not only a query language related to Facebook. GraphQL is not only applicable to social data.</description></item></channel></rss>